

Johannesburg, South Africa

☑ exec@sett.sh | ♠ https://sett.sh | ② sw00 | ≧ sw00 | Ў @settface | ⑤ sett.wai

Summary

Generalist software developer with 6+ years professional experience as a consultant on many different projects and domains, all over the world: from web development to distributed back-end systems; non-profit social development, health and media to retail industry and corporate banking. Big fan of continuous delivery, open source and the "developer experience". Big nerd who cares deeply about craftsmanship and meaningful work.

Though initially pursuing an interest in game development, gained a lot more experience in web development as an autodidact then joined a software consultancy (Alacrity), attracted by opportunity to work on a wide breadth of projects and technologies. Later left to seek out better opportunities and discovered ThoughtWorks where a lot of learning, travel and growth took place. There, was pushed into various technical leadership roles in a short career, based on high technical aptitude and organisation's needs.

Experience _____

ThoughtWorks

South Africa, Uganda, USA, Brazil,

Kenya

CONSULTANT/SENIOR/LEAD DEVELOPER

Apr. 2013 - Dec 2017

- Built project team and laid technical foundations, practices and software delivery approach to replace legacy corporate banking integration in large SA Bank. (Spring Cloud, OpenShift) 7 months
- · Pursued and led the development of app for securities trading over USSD in Kenya (ASP.NET Core)- 3 months
- Implemented features, improved software development on a large team creating flagship Point of Sale (P.O.S.) platform for large US Retailer (iOS WebView, AngularJS, Spring, Microservices) 11 months
- Assisted in technical approach and the development of a greenfield Counter Human-Trafficking system in Uganda (DropWizard with bespoke front-end) - 3 months
- Provided technical leadership on an Anti-counterfeit Medicine verification system over SMS, deployed across Africa (Django, RabbitMQ, Mongo, Vumi) - 14 months
- · Contributed to OpenStack testing framework for large ISP in the US, as part of Quality Engineering team. (Python) 6 months

Alacrity Technologies Pty Ltd

Johannesburg, South Africa

INTERN/JUNIOR DEVELOPER

May 2011 - Oct. 2012

- Built a prototype mobile web app for booking boardrooms (Play! framework, BackboneJS)
- Maintained/extended legacy ASP.NET (VB.NET) application for training fund trustees at a large financial services company. Introduced version control and modern web development practices there.
- Sole developer of online web portal and mobile web app to allow customers to view their pension fund statements online for above-mentioned company (ASP.NET MVC4, JQuery Mobile)

Self-employed

Pretoria/Johannesburg, South Africa Mar. 2008 - Apr 2011, Nov. 2012 - May. 2013

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER AND CONSULTANT

Irregular work desgining and implementing websites for clients and consulting. Flash, HTML, CSS

• Some technical consulting for design agencies: migrating Joomla websites, other such tasks.

Education

UP(University of Pretoria)

Pretoria, South Africa

B.IS IN MULTIMEDIA

Feb. 2006 - Apr. 2010

· A combination of Computer Science, Multimedia and Visual Design culminating in Game Development

Skills_

Languages Python, Java, NodeJS, C#, Shellscript(Bash)

Frameworks web.py, Django, AngularJS, Spring, Express, DropWizard, ASP.NET

DevOps Ansible, Chef, Docker, OpenShift, OpenStack, AWS

Practices Automation, TDD, Pair Programming, Continuous Delivery, Microservices

Tools Vim, IntelliJ, Vagrant, CI (GoCD, Jenkins, ConcourseCI, Bamboo)

Dabbled in... Go, Clojure, Elm

Natural Languages English, Afrikaans, Burmese

MAY 27, 2018 SETT WAI · CURRICULUM VITAE